<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Sharing and collaborating to empower the Infosec community!</description>
    <link>
    https://blog.openthreatresearch.com</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account via Azure Resource Manager Templates to Host Private Files</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently created an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) template where I needed to install a Trusted Certificate Authority (CA) signed SSL certificate on a Windows server VM at deployment time. I tried to pass it as a base64 blob (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;securestring&lt;/code&gt;) to one of the template parameters, but it was still showing in PowerShell logs. Therefore, I decided to use an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/storage/common/storage-account-overview&quot;&gt;Azure Storage Account&lt;/a&gt; to host the certificate in a private container and access it via its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/storage/common/storage-sas-overview&quot;&gt;Shared Access Signature (SAS)&lt;/a&gt; string.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_storage_account_via_arm_private_files</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_storage_account_via_arm_private_files</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Inspecting Default ADFS Identity Provider Initiated Sign On Page with Fiddler and Wireshark</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently created an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OTRF/Blacksmith/tree/master/templates/azure/Win10-AD-ADFS&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to set up an Active Directory Federation Service (ADFS) server. After the deployment, I wanted to learn more about the processes to authenticate a user via the ADFS server and test whether or not authentication was even working before creating a trust with an external service provider (i.e. Microsoft 365).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/adfs_default_idp_initiatedsignon_network</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/adfs_default_idp_initiatedsignon_network</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Adding a Custom Domain to Microsoft 365</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to set up a federated trust between my on-prem Active Directory (AD) in my lab environment and my Microsoft 365 subscription to allow &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/enterprise/plan-for-directory-synchronization?view=o365-worldwide#federated-authentication&quot;&gt;federated authentication&lt;/a&gt; to Office 365 applications. One of the main steps was to add the domain name I used in my on-prem AD lab to the Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant of my Microsoft 365 subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ms365-add-custom-domain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ms365-add-custom-domain</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting a Certificate Signing Request and Activating a Trusted CA Signed SSL Certificate</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had to deploy an Active Directory Federation Services (ADFS) server in my lab environment and integrate it with Office 365. One thing that I did not know was that O365 required a valid SSL certificate from a trusted third party certificate authority (CA).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/csr-ssl-certificate-activation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/csr-ssl-certificate-activation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
