<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> - Articles</title>
    <description>Sharing and collaborating to empower the Infosec community!</description>
    <link>
    https://blog.openthreatresearch.com</link>
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Creating and Starting a Windows Service Remotely Using NtObjectManager Via Remote Procedure Calls (RPC) Over SMB</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to learn more about NtobjectManager and its latest features to create RPC clients and communicate with RPC servers over SMB&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Feb 2021 07:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ntobjectmanager_rpc_smb_scm</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ntobjectmanager_rpc_smb_scm</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to set up a Microsoft Defender for Identity Sensor on a Domain Controller</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently created an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) template to deploy a lab environment to validate the detection of identity attacks and wanted to deploy &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/security/identity-defender&quot;&gt;Microsoft Defender for Identity&lt;/a&gt; to test the protection of on-premises identities and correlation of signals with Microsoft 365.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 Jan 2021 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/microsoft365-identity-sensors-install</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/microsoft365-identity-sensors-install</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Set Up Azure AD Connect to Sync and Federate Custom Domain with On-Prem Directory</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I deployed a lab environment to learn more about federation access between an “on-prem” lab environment and the cloud. I basically wanted to learn how to federate a custom domain in my Azure AD tenant from my Microsoft 365 subscription with on-prem directory.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 10:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_ad_connect_sync_adfs_setup</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_ad_connect_sync_adfs_setup</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>How to Create an Azure Storage Account via Azure Resource Manager Templates to Host Private Files</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently created an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) template where I needed to install a Trusted Certificate Authority (CA) signed SSL certificate on a Windows server VM at deployment time. I tried to pass it as a base64 blob (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;securestring&lt;/code&gt;) to one of the template parameters, but it was still showing in PowerShell logs. Therefore, I decided to use an &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/storage/common/storage-account-overview&quot;&gt;Azure Storage Account&lt;/a&gt; to host the certificate in a private container and access it via its own &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/storage/common/storage-sas-overview&quot;&gt;Shared Access Signature (SAS)&lt;/a&gt; string.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 05:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_storage_account_via_arm_private_files</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/azure_storage_account_via_arm_private_files</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Exploring ADFS Initial Web Traffic and Kerberos Authentication via Fiddler and Wireshark</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently wanted to learn more about the internals of Active Directory Federation Services (ADFS) and created an Azure Resource Manager (ARM) &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/OTRF/Blacksmith/tree/master/templates/azure/Win10-AD-ADFS&quot;&gt;template&lt;/a&gt; to deploy a basic lab environment. As part of my initial research process, I wanted to understand how a user got authenticated before getting an authentication token to access a cloud service. Thefore, I figured it would be good to document some of it by inspecting the network traffic it generates.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/adfs_initial_web_kerberos_network</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/adfs_initial_web_kerberos_network</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Adding a Custom Domain to Microsoft 365</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to set up a federated trust between my on-prem Active Directory (AD) in my lab environment and my Microsoft 365 subscription to allow &lt;a href=&quot;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/microsoft-365/enterprise/plan-for-directory-synchronization?view=o365-worldwide#federated-authentication&quot;&gt;federated authentication&lt;/a&gt; to Office 365 applications. One of the main steps was to add the domain name I used in my on-prem AD lab to the Azure Active Directory (Azure AD) tenant of my Microsoft 365 subscription.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ms365-add-custom-domain</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/ms365-add-custom-domain</guid>
      </item>
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Getting a Certificate Signing Request and Activating a Trusted CA Signed SSL Certificate</title>
        
          <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I had to deploy an Active Directory Federation Services (ADFS) server in my lab environment and integrate it with Office 365. One thing that I did not know was that O365 required a valid SSL certificate from a trusted third party certificate authority (CA).&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 06:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>
        https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/csr-ssl-certificate-activation</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">https://blog.openthreatresearch.com/csr-ssl-certificate-activation</guid>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
